So, you've now seen how we can fit a model by dropping the rows with missing values,
你已经学习了如何删除缺失值来拟合模型
and that's great because now we have models that don't break.
这样很棒 因为不用担心代码报错
However, this means that future observations that are missing those values,
但这也意味着 如果新的观察数据包含缺失值
we're not going to be able to predict for.
就没有办法对其做出预测
In this notebook, we'll take a closer look at this and answer a few questions.
在这次练习中 我们会更深入地看一下这些问题 解答疑问
So, I've read in the data and you can
这里读取了数据
see there's a whole bunch of missing values across the quantitative columns,
可以看到很多数值特征都包含很多缺失值
and this says, "What proportion of individuals in the dataset reported a salary?"
第一个问题是 数据里提供了工资信息的人 其占比是多少?
Do we want, I'm just going to take the num-vars part and salary,
在 num_vars 数据集中选择 Salary 列
isnull.mean, and if we take one minus that.
使用 isnull 函数 取均值 再用 1 减去这个值
So, isnull gives us trues and falses of whether or not a cell is null and this.
isnull 实际上会返回一些 True 和 False 标识是否存在缺失值
So, we get a vector back of trues and falses,
如果取均值的话
and then taking the mean of that gives us the proportion,
得到的其实是没有给出工资的人群比例
and then taking one minus that proportion should give us the proportion.
然后用 1 减去该值 就能得到我们想要的比例了
So, it looks like about 26.2 percent,
应该是 26.2%
and it looks like that matches here,
结果是正确的
and then, the next question is remove the rows associated with nan values and salary,
下一个问题是 删除 num_vars 中 Salary 列存在缺失值的数据
and only salary from the dataframe with num-vars.
将得到的新数据保存在 sal_rem 变量中
So, if you've go to num_vars,
在 num_vars 变量上
and there's a drop NA.
使用 dropna
We saw this subset,
使用这个非常有用的 subset 参数
where we can pass any number of
我们可以传入任意多个列名
columns that we want to just look for nans in those particular ones.
检查这些列中是否存在缺失值
How is any, so I'm going to leave that and axis is 0.
how 参数为默认值 any 然后指定 axis 参数为 0
So, we can see that the thing we get back only has,
可以看到得到的结果中 Salary 是没有缺失值的
they have salaries even though there's nans over here and over here.
尽管其他列还是有很多缺失值
It looks like these ones lined up, okay?
这些行看起来没问题
It looks like that matches the solution as well,
测试结果也说明答案是对的
and then, let's see here, it says,
下一题
"using sal_rm, create X to be a dataframe or matrix of all the numeric features".
使用 sal_rm 数据中的所有数值变量 创建一个 DataFrame X
So you cell RM.
所以这里使用 sal_rm
Create x to be a dataframe with the numeric features.
要将所有数值变量都筛选出来
I'm just going to steal this from up at the top.
其实可以从上面复制
So basically, these are all the numeric features and if we pull out this part,
这些全都是数值型变量 但是需要把 Salary 拿出来
the part that we want to predict is the salary and the way that we
Salary 是我们要预测的目标变量
want to do that is with all the rest of these features, right?
我们想要使用剩下的所有特征
So, we're going to input these as
将这些特征存放在 X 中 准备预测工资
Then it looks like here they're just splitting that into training and test.
这里把数据划分成训练集和测试集
They're using a 30 percent test size and setting a random state,
30% 属于测试集 然后还设置了一个随机种子
and then we're fitting a linear model,
然后我们实例化了一个线性模型
where we basically subtract the mean and divide by
normalize 参数的作用 是将每列的值减去其均值
the standard deviation for each column,
然后再除以其标准偏差 做标准化处理
and then we're going to try to fit that model to our training and test set,
之后尝试用训练集拟合模型
and you can see, if it doesn't work,
可以看到 如果代码没有运行成功
we get this exception that says, "no, it doesn't work".
会进入 except 代码块 提示我们运行失败
So, reasons for that could be Python just likes to break sometimes for no reason at all.
选项 a "Python 偶尔会无理由崩溃"
When I'm frustrated, sometimes it feels like that's true
如果我很沮丧 有时候会感觉这是真的
but I don't think that's actually the case here.
但是正常情况下 肯定不是这个原因
It worked because Python's magic.
选项 b "代码跑通了 Python 就是好!"
That would be great, but it didn't work,
如果这样就好了 但这里代码并没有跑通
and C it broke because we still have missing values in X.
c 选项 "X 数据中还存在缺失值"
So, we tried to fit this model and we
我们尝试拟合模型
saw up here that we still have these missing values,
但是在之前有看到 数据中仍然存在一些缺失值
and so it looks like it's still broke because of them.
所以应该是这个原因
So, I'm going to go C. So,
我选 c
there's missing values in the X matrix, right?
X 里还是有缺失值
So, there's missing values in these columns here,
也就是说 在这些特征里
are still breaking our modeling.
所以模型才会报错
So, all_rm wants to be a dataframe with rows for,
下一个问题 创建 all_rm
and actually, this is suggesting that it should be
把 num_vars 中所有包含缺失值的行都删除后 赋值给 all_rm
So, nan values in any column groups.
也就是不管是哪一列
If there's nan values in any column in here, remove them, right?
只要存在缺失值 其所在行就要被删除
So, this is a dataframe with rows for.
这里的注释写错了
So, num_vars.dropna, and I think we could use all the defaults.
num_vars 然后加上 dropna 应该可以全都用默认参数
I'm just going to do safe, axis equals 0.
但为了保险起见 还是设置一下 axis = 0
And if we run that,
运行代码
and we look at the results,
可以看到结果
it says, "Nice job. That looks right".
回答正确
And it does look like if we didn't specify anything,
如果我们没有指定任何参数
it would have just dropped the ones that we thought,
那就会删除所有存在缺失值的行
and now use this.
现在开始使用
So, this all_rm.
这里的 all_rm
Let's use this all_rm. Again, we're just subsetting it down.
使用 all_rm 同样地 筛选数据子集
So, we want this,
复制这些列名
this is going to be our x matrix again,
这是新的 X_2 矩阵
and then we're going to try to predict salary.
我们用来预测工资
So then, we're going to again just run basically the same code we had before.
接下来 运行这段几乎与之前一样的代码
We're going to do a train test split.
先划分数据集
We're going to fit our- we're instantiating our model,
然后实例化模型
we're going to try to fit it,
再拟合模型
and if it doesn't work,
如果还是报错
it should tell us so.
它会提示我们
Well, we didn't get that print statement,
好的 没有看到这个打印语句
so that means it didn't break.
说明代码没有报错
So, that's A and C. And I guess Python,
所以 a 和 c 是错误的
being magic, is as good a reason as any for us to call this a success.
只有 b 描述代码运行成功 检查结果也是正确的
Then it says use lm_2 to predict y_2_test response values,
下一个问题 使用 lm_2_model 模型来预测 y_2_test 的值
and then obtain the r-squared.
并且计算 R 平方值
So, LM2 to is the model that we want to use,
lm_2_model 是我们要使用的模型
and we want to predict,
我们想要预测
and when we predict what we need to use,
用来预测的数据是
is we need to use the X,
X_2_test
and then we're basically passing all of those inputs
我们把这些值都输入到模型中
into this model so that it can give us what we think should be the predictions,
模型返回预测的结果
and then what we want to do is we want to compare those predictions to
然后我们要将模型的预测结果跟实际值做比较
the actual value and we want to compare it to the y_test_preds.
将 y_2_test 与 y_test_preds 对比
And if we look at that, it looks like here's R-squared value we get.
结果的 R 平方值
It's almost two percent.
差不多有 2%
So, almost two percent of the variability and the response can be explained by our model,
也就是说 我们的模型可以解释将近 2% 的变化
and then it looks like that matches the solution,
看上去答案是正确的
and then there's just this last part.
这是最后一个练习
So, the number of reported salaries in the original dataset.
原始数据集里有多少人给出了自己的工资
So, we can take a look at that in the original dataset,
看一下原始数据集
and so not null should give us basically trues,
使用 notnull 返回很多 True 和 False
so if they're not null,
如果不是 NaN 的话 结果就返回 True
and if we look at how many there are,
看一下有多少个 True
it looks like there's 5,009,
答案是 5009
so that's an A, and then we can get rid of this letter so this doesn't break.
也就是 a 选项 把后面的注释删除 避免报错
The number of salaries predicted using our model,
用模型预测的工资数量
so if we look at the length of y_test_pred,
可以查看 y_test_pred 的长度
y_test_pred is not defined.
y_test_pred 没有定义
Preds, y_test_preds.
好像少一个 s
It looks like it's 645.
结果是 645
So at least in the test set,
至少在测试集中
the number of salaries that we are predicting was 645, right?
我们预测的工资数量是 645
So, if we take this plus the length
如果再加上 y_train 的长度
y_2_train, y_2_test.
y_2_train、y_2_test
So we're predicting 2147 of them,
我们只对 2147 个数据进行了预测
so we're still dropping a whole bunch from the total number of salaries here,
仍然删除了很多数据
so we're not predicting for all of the salaries.
我们并没有针对所有工资进行预测
Basically if they had any missing values in any of the columns we ended up dropping them,
基本上只要数据中有缺失值 就会被删除
so we're still missing about 3,000 of the salaries that we could have had.
我们删除了将近 3000 条样本数据
Okay, if an individual does not rate stack overflow but has a salary.
如果一个人没有给出对 Stack Overflow 的评分 但给出了工资
We still want to predict that salary.
我们仍然是想要预测这种情况的
We're not currently doing it,
现在还没有做这样的操作
as we can see here.
正如在这里看到的
We're not currently predicting them.
现在并没有预测这种数据
So, we still would like to predict that salary and if
但是我们还是希望可以预测的
an individual does not have a job satisfaction but has a salary,
如果一个人没有给出工作满意度 但有工资
we still want to be able to predict that.
我们同样也希望可以作出预测
These are D's and not C's.
答案应该是 d 而不是 c
So, we still want to predict those salaries,
我们还是想预测
we just aren't able to with current model,
只是目前的模型还不行
and then our model predicts salaries for these two individuals described above.
最后一个表述 "我们的模型能够预测上面两种人群"
So, for these two individuals here and that is false.
应该是 False
So, unfortunately right now we're dropping a whole bunch of values still
我们现在弃掉很多的数据 这的确有点可惜
and so in upcoming sections we'll look at how we can impute values,
所以 在下面的课程中 我们会学习如何填充缺失值
and then we can get predictions for all of these.
然后就可以对所有的数据作出预测
But there are also some things that we need to
但是在准备填充数据的时候
be careful of when we start doing imputation.
还有一些事情需要注意